<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Progmatic | by Aman Singh</title>
    <description>A programming blog about some tips and experiences ranging from Competitive Programming to Development
</description>
    <link>http://amanwrites.me/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://amanwrites.me/sitemap.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 22:28:32 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 22:28:32 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.3.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Crontab the beast</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;#An introduction to Cron&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, while creating a cas login program in python, I found crontab. And it was one of the most amazing things that i encountered in linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, those who don’t know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Cron is a utility that helps programmers and developers to schedule commands to be run repeatedly on their machines. Developers use it to set scripts to be run at repeated intervals (Daily, Monthly, Hourly).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With cron, you can schedule maintenance jobs, download the new episode of your favorite TV series and what not!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Installation:
It comes automatically in Ubuntu,Fedora and countless linux distros. But, you can also install it from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unixgeeks.org/security/newbie/unix/cron-1.html&quot; title=&quot;Install cron&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Using it:
cron works with crontab files that contains information about the command to be run and the frequency of that command to be executed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here’s how you create a new job:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check if crontab is installed by executing :
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;crontab -e&lt;/code&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
If cron is installed. This will create a new crontab file and open it with an code.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can add your command there after specifying the time and date of execution or the frequency of its execution.
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;For more info on how to write a crontab file [write crontab file][https://corenominal.org/2016/05/12/howto-setup-a-crontab-file/ “Writing crontab file”].&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope, you also find crontab extremely useful, like me ;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://amanwrites.me/scripts/2017/02/17/That-Awesome-Crontab.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://amanwrites.me/scripts/2017/02/17/That-Awesome-Crontab.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>scripts</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
